Kwaku Prempeh

ABOUT ME

With a background of creativity courtesy of a Music Technology degree and after working in the customer service industry for many years, I decided that I was ready for a new and exciting challenge and change career paths completely. I've always had an interest in all things tech, web and software driven, so the Web Development Immersive course at General Assembly London was the perfect solution for me.

At General Assembly, I learnt the fundamentals of programming and started experimenting with full-stack websites and apps. I'm very enthusiastic and excited to find a Junior Developer role to help harness and unlock my creativity and grow my passion for new technologies. I am very keen to utilise my current skills and develop new ones, with a desire to work within an organisation that will offer training and career progression.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Development Immersive - September - December 2015

General Assembly

Full time intensive three-month coding bootcamp, covering a range of topics from the basics of programming to both client and server side languages and frameworks including JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, AJAX, MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, NodeJS, HTML and CSS, as well as providing experience of working in an agile environment.

PROJECTS

Dirty Dice - My first GA assignment was to build a game in vanilla JavaScript. I choose to build a simple two player dice game with a twist of street craps and bowling.

Technologies: HTML, CSS & jQuery **Github:** github.com/KwakesProject/

dirty_dice

Weblink: dirtydice.herokuapp.com

HackJammer: - A group project with 3 other developers. HackJammer is a very compact app utilising APIs from various event hosting sites to crawl information and then using the Google Maps and Geocoder API to render all hackathons and meetups directly onto a full screen map.

Technologies: Node JS, Express, Bootstrap, Google Maps API, Geocoder API, Eventbrite API

Github Repo: github.com/ KwakesProject/wdi-project-3 **XE-Size** - A fitness and personal workout webapp for the benefit of both personal trainers and their clients.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, SASS, Foundation, Devise, Carrierwave, RMagick, AWS, CanCanCan

Github: github.com/KwakesProject/

xe-size

Weblink: xe-size.herokuapp.com

Prattle' Messenger:- A cross-platform instant messaging application that is the product of a WDI-16 24 hour Hacka-thon. The app is responsive to allow users to access it on desktop or on the go using a smartphone.

Technologies: Ruby on rails, Devise, Postgresql & socketChat.

Github: github.com/KwakesProject/prattle

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT



+44 (0) 7940 368 675



kwakesproject.com



kwakesproject@gmail.com



github.com/KwakesProject



uk.linkedin.com/in/ kwakuprempeh



@KwakesProject

TECHNICAL SKILLS





















EDUCATION



Web Development Immersive General Assembly

London

September - December 2015



BA (Hons) Music Technology Thames Valley University

Ealing

October 2001- May 2004



BTEC National Diploma in Performing Arts

Richmond Upon Thames College Twickenham

September 1999 - July 2001

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

Toyota & Lexus Team Manager

Serco Global Services

September 2011 - July 2015

Responsible for the day to day management of the Toyota & Lexus Contact Centre, which consists of inbound call handling, outbound marketing activity, web chat, email & white mail handling. Ensuring Service Level Agreements and Key Performance Indicators are achieved as well as team targets. Monitoring calls and providing constructive feedback in order to try and improve call skills and staff development.

Customer Service Manager

Odeon Cinema

September 2000 - September 2012

Managing and leading the team to achieve exceptional results focusing on great customer service. Responsible for staff recruitment, training, development and supervision of up to sixty employees, as well as handling the day-to-day cash management and end of day banking procedures. Other key roles included reviewing team performance, identify training needs and seek opportunities for coaching and carrying out training activities.

CERTIFICATIONS

Management Aspiration Programme

Serco Global Services

September 2014

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Music, sports and movies are my main loves in life. I play football every Saturday afternoon for a local club and a loyal Arsenal fan. I also love every opportunity to get myself on a dance floor and showoff my moves. I sometimes DJ parties and events whenever the opportunity comes and also produce music tracks in my spare time. I even worked with a few UK artists when they first started like Chipmunk & Wretch 32. Twelve years in a cinema will show you that I could watch and talk about movies all day and I try to get up to date with the latest releases and upcoming movies.